Total Experience: 13 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

# N.CHINNUSAMY () Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Software Design,IT Project Management, SDLC, Requirement Gathering, HTML, CSS, jQuery,Javascript,Angularjs,ASP.Net, MVC, WCF, Web API, SQL Server, Elastic Search, Splunk, Fiddler



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer - IT

Current Company: Dell International Services

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Coimbatore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Team Lead, Software Development, Software Design, Defect Tracking, Technical

Documentation,IT Project Management,SDLC,Requirement

Gathering, jQuery, Javascript, Angularjs, ASP. Net, Splunk, Fiddler, Web Services

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

### Summary

Over 12+ years of experience in software designing, developing and testing of windows and client-server web based applications using .NET Framework & SQL and NoSQL Databases with Agile and Waterfall Development Methodology. Experienced in developing technical documentation in various stages of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC). Contribute to development of new tools and automation that ensures the service can be optimized and tuned with minimal human intervention.

Track down defects and come up with innovative solutions to improve reliability and availability using tools like Splunk, Riverbed

mprove application reliability and resiliency as input to technology roadmaps.

Share real world implementation challenges and recommend new capabilities that would

simplify adoption and drive greater value from use of Dell's infrastructure services. Actively built and managed relationship with clients and stakeholders

## **Work Experience**

**Dell International Services** as Senior Software Engineer - IT Jun 2019 to Till Date

Content Studio(CMS)

Env.: HTML 5, CSS 3, Angular JS 1.5, C#, MVC 5, Web API, Elasticsearch,

Splunk, Riverbed

Role: Dev & Site Reliability Engineer Duration: Jun 2017 - Present A content generator application used by world-renowned enterprises like

Dell, Pricing. It enables content and business operation teams to

manage the full life-cycle of content management.

Managed all facts of production stability including but not limited to

performance improvement, issue triage, bug fixes and feature development.

Involved in "Black Friday" and "Cyber Monday" sales activities.

The data comes through various ports such as harmony and CNET port as

MQ messages along with Rich Media content. The content sent and

received as messages.

Experienced in triaging various facts of applications by using industry

leading tools such as Splunk and Riverbed

#### Sonata Software Ltd as Consultant

May 2017 to May 2019

#### URC Infotec, Erode as Technical Specialist

Aug 2009 to May 2017

myCare - Scrubs & Claim Processing

Env.: HTML 5, CSS 3, Angular JS, C#, MVC 5, Web API, SQL Server

Role: Team Leader Duration: Jun 2016 - May 2017

Claim module allows user to track the receivables and outstanding against

the client accurately.

The input for the claims is from both application & interface. In case of interface, we receive the information through the HL7 messages and by processing the HL7 messages we get the required information for the claims. Scrubber tool validates the set of pre-defined HAAD OR DHA rules against the claims and ensures that the claims are ready for Invoice Generation. Remittance, Write Off, Credit note, can be captured against the Invoice Accepted status claims alone. Activity Cancellation, excluding a claim from Invoice can also be done.

Designed the product from the requirement stage and lead the development team

CIMS CRM

Env.: HTML 5, CSS 3, Java Script, JQuery, C#, SQL Server 2012

Role: Team Leader Duration: Aug 2013 - July 2015

CIMS CRM is customer relationship management software dedicated for the real estate builders.

CRM includes Feasibility Study, Land Management, Project Maintenance, Pre Sales, Post Sales, Maintenance, Demand Letter

Creation etc.

The project involves gathering business requirements from users for enhancement related tickets.

Designed the product from the requirement stage and lead the development team

#### 4. CIMS (Construction Information Management System)

Env.: VB.Net, Infragistics, SQL Server 2008

Role: Developer & Team Leader Duration: Oct 2009 - July 2013

CIMS (Construction Information Management System) is a totally integrated and customized multi-user, multi-location ERP

System for meeting the information needs of any organization engaged in the business of construction. It covers sixteen modules, including core module focusing on Remote Site Project Planning & Execution, Material Management, Finance, Human

Resource, Billing, and Monitoring.

Human resource module includes Recruitment Process, Candidate Profile, Employee Profile, Staff TDS, Employee Payroll.

Attendance, Leave, Promotion and Arrear, Training and Development, Joining Formalities like Joining Report, offer letter

The project involves gathering business requirements from users for enhancement related tickets. Upon successful resolution of

issues in each ticket, the documents/fix will be specified to the user for UAT and implementation.

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Muthayammal Engq College, Rasipuram, TN in 2005

### IT Skills

| Skill Name                            | Version Last Used Experience |
|---------------------------------------|------------------------------|
| HTML 5,CSS 3,Java Script, JQuery      |                              |
| AngularJS,Web Services , WCF, Web API |                              |
| VB.Net,C# .Net, MVC 5,ASP.Net         |                              |
| Infragistics, SignalR, MSMQ           |                              |
| SQL server, MySql                     |                              |
| Elastic Search 5.5.2 , Kibana 5.5.2   |                              |
| Splunk , RiverBed                     |                              |
| Crystal Reports,Bartender             |                              |
| Fiddler, TFS, VSS , gitHub, TeamCity  |                              |
| Octopus , ServiceNow                  |                              |

# Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  | Proficient  |      |       |       |
| Tamil    | Expert      |      |       |       |
| Kannada  | Beginner    |      |       |       |

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: OBC - non-creamy Physically Challenged: No